Nguyen Dinh

Junior Full Stack Node.js, Flask, PHP Developer









A recent B.Sc. in Computer Science graduate with 4 years of Front-End Web Development and 2 years of Full-Stack Development. I am a communicative team-player who is both adaptive and creative. I aim to diversify my knowledge and collaborate on exciting projects with passionate people.

Education

B.Sc. Computer Science - 2019

Concordia University

Montreal, Quebec

B.Sc. Anatomy & Cell Biology - 2012

University of Saskatchewan

Saskatoon, Saskatchewan

Technical Knowledge

Front-end

ES6 HTML5 CSS3 TypeScript
jQuery Bootstrap
SASS ReactJS Redux
Material Design Photoshop Mock-ups
SEO Analytics Tag Managers/Pixels

Back-end

Node.js Express EJS Handlebars
npm npm-scripts
Flask Jinja venv pip
PHP7 WordPress Apache
MongoDB Postgres MySQL Sqlite3
Heroku Electron cPanel

Others

Source Control markdown APIs
Agile Development REST
Windows Linux Command line
HTTP/TCP DNS/IP
Python C++ Java openGL
Microservices PaaS SaaS
Natural Language Processing NLTK
Information Retrieval Machine
Learning

Experience

Web Developer/Webmaster - INMR

Zimmar Holdings

https://www.inmr.com

2017 - Present

Developing and managing WordPress Multi-sites

- Programmed and deployed highly customized themes
- Maintenance and modern improvements to legacy software
- · Enhanced IT infrastructure and networking
- Creation of a custom of dynamic news feed
- Development of advertising solutions and implementations
- Created documentation and copy writing
- Production of 2 offline desktop applications (Web/Electron)

Front-end Application Developer – McGill Burney Centre McGill University

https://www.readingwithausten.com

2017 - Present

Designed, developed, deployed a virtual re-imaging of Jane Austen's beloved library.

- Iterative Agile development process
- · Produced front-end, client-side solutions
- Designed, prototyped, and implemented UX and UI
- · Constructed library meta-data search engine
- Applied web optimizations (content/network) and usage analytics
- Compiled project to an Electron desktop application

Web Developer

Freelance

2015 - Present

Helping clients reach audiences with their brand

- Creating mock-ups and actualizing design needs
- Supplying customized content, copy writing and media creation
- IT support, troubleshooting, maintenance
- Managing client hosting and deployment
- Customized programs and micro-services
- Designing usable interfaces for client administration

Soft Skills

Story telling Presentations
Written and oral communication
Self-motivated Inventive Analytical
Organized Resourceful Perceptive
Team Player Leadership
Constructive Positive Diligent

Personal Interests

<u>Theatre Improvisation Stand-up</u>
<u>Music production Music performance</u>
<u>Spoken Word Poetics</u>
<u>Volleyball Ultimate Frisbee Soccer</u>

References

Available upon request

Volunteer Work

Mentor - Ladies Learning Code/Teachers Learning Code

Canada Learning Code

2017 - Present

Canadian charity looking to increase digital and programmatic literacy

- Leading instructions and modules
- Guiding students through realizing programming skills

Web Developer – Conference Food Bank

Freelance

2019 - Present

A start-up helping conferences donate their excess food to local charities

- Designing technical specifications and implementing prototypes
- Functional integration of volunteer network, donation calendar, and charity registration

Projects

Software Developer

SoftSpoke

2017 - Present

Start-up aiming to bring technological accessibility and machine learning to the field of Speech & Language Pathology

- Prototyping of user customizable storybook reading application
- Developing user interfaces for NLP tools and models
- Independent research into grammar models and word embeddings
- Software narrative assessment and creation tools

Web Developer/Content Creation

shefindsoldpoems

2009 - Present

Internet home for personal creative projects in music, writing, photography, and programming

- MongoDB, React.js, Node, Express application
- Music production, audio mixing and mastering
- Photo editing and optimizations with GIMP and Photoshop
- Testing grounds for front-end interaction design and user experience